bobwp.com 2019-11-02

# BobWP Policy

BobWP is owned and run by Bob Dunn. The website address is: [https://bobwp.com](https://bobwp.com/).

### Disclosure

#### The Stuff We Write About

We educate through tips, tutorials and insights on all aspects of starting and running a WooCommerce online store.

#### Affiliate Links Disclosure

Yes, this is one of the primary sources of our income. You are going to find a lot of links here on our site, and many of them are affiliate links. A large percentage of them are services and products we have used for a long time ourselves. There are others scattered in posts on products and services we have tested and feel you should know about. If you click on any of those links, we make a few bucks and you don’t pay anymore. This blog is our business, not a side gig to collect a little cash, so we appreciate any time you purchase through one of these links.

#### Podcast Sponsors

Our podcast has up to two sponsors per episode. They are clearly noted on both the post and in the podcast. Their sponsorship helps us continue to produce our podcasts by covering out-of-pocket costs and production costs.

#### Partners

Anyone listed as a partner on our site is a result of a long relationship we have had with them. Support has gone both ways with these partners.

### About Our Site and Content

#### What We Don’t Talk About

Any site that resells WooCommerce plugins, themes or extensions that are not their own property and are developed and owned by another vendor, will not be shared or mentioned on this site. Even though GPL allows this, we don’t feel this is ethical or to the advantage of the user or owner of the products and service.

#### Guest Posts

We do not accept or publish unsolicited guest posts. Rarely do we publish guest posts and they are by invite only to people we know will produce content that fits our site.

#### Links and Sponsored Links

First off, we will not add any link to a post that is solicited or unsolicited. Secondly, we do not accept money for links. If you have a link you want us to place in any of our content, whether for free or paid, we do not accept them.

#### Infographics

Please don’t send us a request to post your infographic, as we do not add those upon request as well.

#### Nothing Is Set In Stone

Yes, we can and will at times change stuff in our posts without notification to our readers. We can’t help it. We like to keep things updated when we can.

### Affiliations

We are not directly affiliated with WordPress, WooCommerce or Automattic.

### Privacy Policy – What personal data we collect and why we collect it

#### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. [The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Contact forms

Our forms collect requested information that you provide, and your website URL and Internet Protocol. This information isn’t used for anything but to reply if you have submitted a question or interest in talking to me.

#### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

Cookies are also stored when clicking on an affiliate link on our site to track the sales on the third-party site you are directed to. Those cookies typically expire around 30 days depending on the vendor. No personal information is stored on our site when you click them, and you will need to check out the privacy policy of any other site that you continue to do business with.

#### Analytics

We use Google Analtyics here on our site and traffic data is collected and stored there for 26 month. We collect non-personally-identifying information that includes referring site, time and date of your visit, browser and mobile type and country and language You can learn more about how [Google stores information on their privacy policy here.](https://privacy.google.com/businesses/)

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

#### Your Data and Our Partners

Here is a list of any the data and who we share it with and links to their privacy policy.

 **MailChimp** – If you subscribe to our weekly update, you give us your email only. This information, plus your IP is then stored at MailChimp. We do not share this information with anyone else and [here is their privacy policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

 **Google Analytics** – As stated above, information on your browser, navigation and when you visit our are captured but no personal information is captured or retained.

 **Vimeo and YouTube** – We embed a lot of video from these two platforms on our site. These two sites may capture your IP and browser info, but are never shared with me.

 **Akismet** – We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself)

 **iThemes Sync** – This web site uses a third party service to manage administrative tasks. If you leave a comment, submit personal information via a contact form, or otherwise exchange personal details with us, it is possible that we may use this service to manage that data. Please visit the iThemes Privacy Policy for more information regarding the way they handle their data.

### What we share with others

What personal information your store shares with external sources depends on which third-party payment processor plugins you are using to collect subscription payments. We recommend that you consult with their privacy policies to inform this section of your privacy policy.

If you are using PayPal Standard or PayPal Reference transactions please see the [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) for more details.

Most of our other plugins on this site, if any information is shared, it’s simple analytics and we can provide more information if requested.

#### Sponsorship Payments

When you purchase a sponsorship, you will be sent an PayPal or Stripe invoice. No transactions occur and no data is collected or retained for payments on our site.

Please see the [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) for more details.

Please see [Stripe Global Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy) for more information.

### How long we retain your data

 **Comments (WordPress default)** – If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

 **Site Registration (WordPress default)** – For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

 **Contact Forms (Gravity Forms)** – any form data is saved for 6 months and then is totally deleted from our account.

### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes

### Questions?

If something is still nagging at your or we haven’t covered it, feel free to **[contact us](https://bobwp.com/contact/).** We promise we won’t bite.

 **This policy can be updated at any time and was last updated October 17, 2019.**
